字幕转换：nickkest
星影业奉献
导演卡尔法兰克林
主演丹尼新华盛顿
片名蓝魔鬼
汤姆西摩尔
珍尼花贝尔斯
It was summer 1948.
那是在1948的夏天
And I needed money.
那时候我很需要钱
After going door-to-door all day, I was back again at Joppy's bar...
在摈家摈户地技工作后我又回到了佐皮的小酒馆里
... trying to figure out where to look for work the next day.
好好的想想我第二天该去哪里技工作
The newspapers was going on and on about the city elections...
每一份报纸上都是关于市长选举的事．．
... like they was really gonna change somebody's life.
好像他们真的能够改变某人的一生似的．
My life had already changed when I lost my job 3 weeks before.
自从3个星期以前我丢了工作以后我的生活倒是真的改变了
For example, one of the white guys pulls a double shift.
假如是一个白人家伙一天轮两次班
lf he says he's too tired to work overtime, you don't fire them.
如果他说他已经厌倦了加班你们应该不会解雇他吧
That's all you have to say?
你要说的就只有这些?
No, that's not all. l need....
不，还有．我得
l need to pay my mortgage and eat.
我还要还贷款，吃饭
l need a house to live in and clothes on my back. l need the job.
我要住，要穿．我需要钱
l'm sorry, fella, l gotta get back to work.
我很抱歉，伙计我要回去工作了
My name's not ''fella.''
我的名字不叫”伙计
My name's not ''fella.'' My name is Ezekiel Rawlins.
我的名字不叫”伙计我叫做伊泽科尔．g林斯
Catch you later, Joppy.
佐皮，我迟点再付你钱
Watch the marble, damn it! What'd l tell you?
小心我的大理石桌面该死的 你有什么看法
How much you think they're paying at Douglas Aircraft?
你觉得道格拉斯飞机公司的薪水应该是多少
l don't know.
我不知道
Come on over here.
过来
There's somebody l want you to meet.
我介绍一个人给你认识
Come on, this is a friend of mine.
过来，这是我的朋友
Easy, this is Mr. Albright.
伊斯，这是奥尔布莱特先生
-Call me DeWitt, Easy. -How you doing?
叫我戴维新伊斯你好
Take a seat.
坐
Mr. Albright and me...
奥尔布莱特先生和我
...go way back to before the war.
还没有上战场就回来了
Back when l was still in the fight game.
应该是我还在战场上的时候你就回来了
Ever seen this guy fight?
你看过这个家伙打仗的样子吗?
Every time Joppy stepped in the ring, you knew you would see...
每一次佐皮踏进包围圈的时候你应该也能猜到会发生什么事
...some knockdown-dragout fisticuffs.
锐不可当D拼命的挥动着他的拳
-Where you from? -Houston.
D你的老家在哪?D休斯顿
Joppy's hometown.
佐皮的老家也在那儿
Need a job?
你要技工作吗?
Yeah. Easy always trying to do better.
没错．伊斯总是尽力把事情做的最好
Easy's one of a few coloured men around here who owns his own house.
伊斯在这个地方是少数几个拥有房子的黑人之
He paying the mortgage every month, just like y'all folks.
他每个月都要换贷款就像你们这些家伙一样
Property owner, huh?
拥有财产，喂?
These big companies don't give a damn.
那些大公司根本就不会遭到谴责
l got out of that racket long ago.
我早就离开那个飞机公司了
lf you need a job, drop by this address, 7:00.
如果你需要一份工作7点来这个地方
Tonight.
今晚
What kind of work you do?
你是做什么的?
l do favours.
我是来帮忙的
l do favours for friends.
我来帮一个朋友
Drop by.
顺便
Who was that?
他是谁
Just somebody l know. Businessman.
只是我认识的一个人做生意的
-Businessman, huh? -Yeah, he is.
D做生意的，哈?D是的，没错
Ain't nothing to worry about.
没有什么好紧张的
When I'm told there's nothing to worry about...
当别人告诉我没有什么好紧张的时候．
...I look to see if my fly is open.
我会看看我的拉链有没有开
All the way home, all I thought about was a chance to make some money.
回家的时候，我一路上都在想怎样做个机会晚点钱
I first came out to Los Angeles when I got home from the war in Europe...
我刚到洛杉机的时候是我刚才欧洲打仗回来的时
... with $300 in my pocket and the G.I. Bill.
口袋里只有300美金和一张军票
很多有色人种涌到德克萨斯州就像
A lot of coloured folk from Texas and Louisiana moved to California...
大批的路易斯安娜州的人涌到加利福尼亚一样．．．
... to get them good jobs in the shipyards and aircraft companies.
到造船厂和飞机制造厂去找一份比较好工作
Now, me, myself, I was a machinist.
现在，我我本来是一个机械机工
And the first thing I did when I saved enough money was to buy me a house.
也是第一份可以让我存钱买房子的工作
Man, I loved coming home to my house.
嘿，我喜欢回到居于我自己的房子的感党
I don't know.
我不知道
I guess maybe I just loved owning something.
我想我只是很喜欢拥有某样东西的感党
-l'll knock down the trees in the back. -Leave my trees alone.
我可以帮你把院子里的树砍掉D别动我的树
Leave my trees! Get on!
别动我的树 走开
I was feeling pretty desperate that evening.
那天晚上我感到很感到很绝望
In a week, I'd be 2 months behind on my mortgage.
再过一星期，我的贷款就拖欠的时间就满2个月了
And I wasn't about to lose my house.
而我不想失去我的房子
But a chill running up the back of my neck was telling me...
但是一股塞战从我的背急串到我的脖子上
...I was about to make a bad decision.
让我感觉到我会作出一个很坏的决定
Yeah, Albright made me nervous.
是的，奥尔布赖特让我觉得紧张
He reminded me of a fella in Texas named Mouse.
他让我想起了在德克萨斯州一个叫麦斯的家伙
-Let's dump this thing. -Isn't this your friend's car?
我们开点把这部车开走这不你朋友的车吗?
-What'd you do? -Just drive.
D你要干什么?你只要负责开车就好
What did you do?
你都干了些什么?
So, want the job?
你要做这个工作吗?
lt depends.
看情况
l don't wanna get mixed up in nothing.
我不想卷进任何是非里
Walk out the door in the morning...
早上你走出那扇门的时候
...you're mixed up in something.
你已经被卷进是非里了
Only thing is, if you're mixed up to the top or not.
只有你是否在这个游戏中是否站上风的区别
l'm just looking for somebody. For a friend.
我只是在找人．帮一个朋友的忙
Daphne Monet.
望芜“摩耐特
Fianc茅e of Todd Carter. She's been gone two weeks.
托普卡特的未婚妻．她已经失踪2星期了
lt upset the man so much, he stopped running for mayor.
他很伤心，他已经停止了竞选市长的活动了
-l've never seen her. -That's a shame.
D我从未见过她．D你该感到羞“隗
Daphne has a predilection for the company of Negroes.
望芜有跟黑人交朋友的偏好
She likes jazz, pig's feet and dark meat.
她喜欢贾士乐猪脚和红肉
'' Predilection.''
偏好
l'd go looking for her myself...
我应该自己去找她的
...but l'm not of the right persuasion.
但是我的说服力不够
What do you want from me?
你要我做什么?
What do you mean?
你是什么意思?
-What do l do? -Get her location.
我的工作是什么?找到她
Mr. Carter wants to make up with her.
卡特先生要和她修补关系
$1 00.
100美金
l pay in advance.
这是定金
$1 00.
100美金
To tell you where she's at?
告诉你她在哪就可以了吗?
-That's right. -And that's all?
D没错就这些?
That's all.
就这些
Joppy tells me you used to frequent an illegal club.
佐皮告诉我你经常去一家非法经营的酒吧
John's.
约翰酒吧
Somebody saw Daphne there a few nights ago.
有人在几天前在那里看到她
Start tonight.
从今天晚上开始
Whoa, that's enough. Thank you.
哇，够了．谢谢
-l'm gonna see you later. -All right, yeah.
我们迟点再见面D好的
l told you it's a grocery store.
我告诉过你这里是杂货店
How you doing, baby?
宝贝，你好吗?
Mister, l told you, you can't be in here harassing folks.
先生，我告诉过你你不能在这儿妨碍我做生意
What's going on?
发生了什么事情?
l paid these damn cops off, and they're rousting my customers.
我付钱给这些该死的警察他们居然还赶走我的客人
That's what he get for messing with that white woman.
那就是为什么会和那个白种女人站在那里
Don't pay him no attention.
不要理他
l done rung for Junior to take care of that.
我已经叫了姐尼尔下来处理这个事了
They got nobody but Deucy and them tonight.
今天晚上他们只抓到了朵苗和那几个人
l had Holiday on Thursday. Yeah, you missed it.
我星期四放假是的，你很想1
Wait for the cops to leave. Take Easy upstairs.
等到警察走了以后再说吧带伊斯上楼
And if he's still down here, come on back and throw his ass out.
如果他还站在这儿你就过来把他一脚揣出去
Get out of here. You better be gone.
你就好现在就滚出去
l'll be here waiting.
我会在这里等的
You just wait, mister. Just keep waiting.
先生，那你就等吧慢慢等
Mr. McGee, there is no upstairs.
麦墓尔先生这里只有一层
-Got another cigarette? -Sure.
要再来一根吗?D当然
Zapattas. How you smoke these damn things?
赞帕塔．你怎么会抽这些该死的东西
You the only Negro smoke Mexican cigarettes.
你是唯一一个抽墨西哥雪茄的黑人
Last time l heard these fellas was back in Houston.
上次我听说这些家伙回去休斯顿了
The night Mouse pulled me off you.
那天晚上麦斯把我给甩开
-That's how you remember it? -That's the way it was.
D你记得的是这样子的吗?D事实就是这样
Look here...
听着
...admit that you helped Mouse kill Navrochet.
你现在承认你帮麦斯杀死诺勒切了吧
Get off that. You know l didn't have nothing to do with that.
好了．你知道这和我没有什么关系
Where the white women?
那个白人女人在哪?
-l pay them no mind. -l bet.
我没有注意过她们D我敢赌你有
Like you didn't help Mouse kill his stepfather.
就像你没有帮麦斯杀他的继父一样
Did you help him kill his stepbrother too?
你也帮他杀了的他继父的儿子吗?
Give me a setup and a Coke back.
给我一杯可乐
Have you seen a girl named Dahlia, Delila, something like that?
你有没有见一个女孩叫做望而尔朵而尔，或是类4以这样的名字?
White girl, supposed to be something to see.
白人女孩有人在这里看见过她
lf l do see her, l'll keep her to myself.
如果我看到她我一定会留着自己用
Keep the change.
零钱给你了
Deacon Odell.
迪森“欧戴尔
How you doing tonight?
你好吗?
lt's going all right. lt sure is going.
很好．怎么会不好
Easy Rawlins, is that you?
伊斯．g林斯，是你吗?
-Ain't jumped out of no windows yet? -Not yet, Dupree.
D你还没有摆脱失业的困境吗?D还没有，杜瑞
-You know Coretta, don't you? -Sure, how you doing?
D你认识克拉塔，是吗?D当然，你好?
l'm all right.
我很好
This is Odell.
这是欧戴尔
Can we sit with y'all?
我们可以跟你们一起坐吗?
Sure.
当然
We miss you down at the plant.
整个农场的人都很想你
Benny would've gave you your job back, right?
班尼不会再把工作给回你了是吗?
All you had to do was go and say you was sorry.
你只要去道歉就可以了
l'm sorry, all right. Give me that bourbon.
好吧，我道歉．把波夯威士忌酒给我
Any man without his paycheck is sure enough sorry.
那不到他的薪水的人有足够的理由该感到抱歉
l got it. Your money ain't no good.
我付钱．让你花钱不好
-This one's mine. -You sure?
D这是我的了D你确定吗?
-You the one ain't got no job. -You the one ain't got no money.
D你没有工作了D你没有钱
Y'all seen a white girl named Dahlia...
你们见过你一个叫望而尔的白人女孩吗．
...or Delila? First name start with a '' D.''
或者是叫朵而尔?名字以”D’开头的
Coretta got herself a job at the phone company.
克拉塔在“家电话公司找到了工作
Congratulations. They ain't hiring no mans down there?
恭喜你．他们要不要请男职员
You all right, Odell?
你还好吧，欧戴尔?
He used to play till the cock crowed.
他总是留到天亮公鸡叫了才回去
That old cock don't crow nearly so much now.
现在的老公鸡不大叫早了
l better get on home.
我要回家了
You'd be sorry if you go.
如果你现在走的话你会后悔的
l'd be sorry if l stay too.
如果我留在这我才会后悔
Good night.
晚安
Daphne asleep by now...
望芜已经睡着了
...so you can't get none of that tonight.
所以今天晚上你什么消息也打听不到
Go around here telling everybody '' Dahlia.''
跑到这里来到处打听’望而尔
Her name is Daphne.
她的名字叫望芜
Do you know her?
你认识她吗?
-Where you want me to put him? -This ain't my house!
D你要我把他放在哪里?这不是我的房子
This ain't my house.
这也不是我的房子
Just throw him on the bed.
把他仍到床上吧
Shut up.
闭嘴
Be careful. The door.
小心一点．那扇门
Threw him out of his place because he couldn't pay rent.
因为他付不起房租就把他赶出来
l shouldn't let him sleep here.
我不能让他睡在这里
-Damn, that Negro's heavy. -l know, l know.
该死的，这个黑鬼真重我知道，我知道
l need a cigarette.
我想要抽根烟
That all you need?
你只要抽烟吗?
Sun catch me tiptoeing outside your door, what your neighbours say?
如果太阳出来的时候让你的邻居看到
我从你的房子里走出来他们会怎么说?
All right, Easy.
好的，伊斯
Dupree fell asleep on me...
杜瑞跟我睡党
...and you just gonna walk out on me like l was dog food, huh?
而你就像嫌弃狗食一样嫌弃我，哼?
Girl, what you talking about?
女孩，你在说什么?
Now, come on.
现在，过来
Coretta, your man is in the next room.
克拉塔你的男人就睡在隔壁房间
Tell me about your friend Daphne.
告诉我关于你的朋友望芜的事
Why you keep asking about her?
你为什么老是问起她?
Coloured women ain't good enough for you no more?
有色人种的女人不对你的胃口了吗
That ain't it.
不是那样的
Shoot.
来吧
What if he heard something?
如果他听见了怎么办?
He asleep.
他睡着了
Daddy, that's it!
爸爸，就是这样
That's it.
就是这样
You're hitting my spot. You're hitting my spot.
操我．操我
Easy, Easy, Easy.
伊斯，伊斯，伊斯
l can't give up that much loving, daddy.
我不能放弃，色鬼
-Not the way things is. -What things?
我们不能这样一怎么了?
He's right in the next room.
他就在隔壁的房间
Forget about Dupree. You got me going.
忘掉杜瑞．我们继续
lt ain't right, doing this right in the next room.
我们在隔壁房间这样做是不对的
All you're doing is nosing after my friend Daphne.
你只想要打听我的朋友望芜的事
No, baby.
不是的，宝贝
-That's just a job. -What job?
D那只是工作D什么工作?
-Some man want me to find her. -What man?
有个男人要我找到她D什么男人?
l don't know what man.
我也不知道是什么男人
l don't want nobody but you.
我什么人也不认识只是认识你
Daphne's my friend. l can't do it.
望芜是我的朋友我不能这样做
Just a little bit, okay?
再来一下，好吗?
Just a little bit.
再来一下
Just a little bit, baby.
再来一下，宝贝
Oh, you're hitting my spot.
眶，操我
You're hitting my spot.
操我
And I went on hitting her spot until just before sunup.
我一直操她到太阳出来以前
I realized Coretta had found out as much about what I was up to...
我意识到克拉塔知道的不比
...as I had found out about Daphne Monet.
我知道的关于望芜．摩耐特的多
As it turned out, Todd Carter wasn't the only man in Daphne's life.
看起来，托普?卡特并不是望芜生命中唯一的男人
She was shacking up with a smalltime coloured gangster named Frank Green.
她还跟一个叫弗兰克“格林黑人强盗同居过一小段时间
Coretta had the nerve to charge me $1 0 for that information.
克拉塔还胆敢因为这条消息收了我1o美金
Everybody was in business in L.A.
在洛杉机每个人都是生意人
That morning, I waited for Albright to call.
那天上午我一直在等奥尔布莱特的电话
I tried to feel good about paying a few bills...
付了一些帐单了以后我试着让自己因此而高兴起来
...and I mean just a few.
而我只是有一点点的感党
Shoot, a loaf of bread was damn near 1 5 cents.
妈的，一条面包就要15美分
It was easy money.
这种钱真容易赚
Too easy.
太容易了
Bye, Easy!
再见，伊斯
-Where you going, Sophie? -Back to Texas.
D你要去哪里，素非亚?回德克萨斯去
Too fast for me out here.
这里的生活节奏对于我来说太快了
Get on away from the house!
离那房子远一点
Get away from that tree!
离那颗树远点
Get on away from that tree!
Get away from that tree!
离那颗树远点
Easy, how you doing?
伊斯，你好
I hope you have good news for me.
我希望你有好消息给我
-Mr. Albright, is that you? -Sure is. What's shaking?
奥尔布赖特先生，是你吗?是我．什么东西在晃?
-l got what you want. -Hold on to that.
我打听到了你要的东西现在别说
I only do business in person. Tell you what.
我做生意要面对面的我告诉你
You come out here to Malibu. Meet me at Fishermans Pier in an hour.
你现在来玛利布．我们一个小时以后渔夫码头见
Malibu? Mr. Albright, l don't--
玛利布?奥尔布赖特先生，我不知道
lt's pretty out here.
这的风景很不错
lt's all right.
还行
l'm from Des Moines, lowa.
我来自得梅因，阿华州
Where are you from?
你来自哪里?
Texas.
德克萨斯
Do they have an ocean in Texas?
德克萨斯有海吗?
-A gulf in Texas. -Barbara! Where are you?
D那儿有一个海湾巴巴拉 你在哪?
Your friends are looking for you.
你的朋友在拢你
Who cares?
My sister brought me here because my parents made her.
我的姐娜g我带到这儿因为我的父母把她赶了出来
All she wants to do is make out with Herman and smoke cigarettes.
她满脑子只想着她的男朋友和抽烟
What you doing here?
你们在这儿干什么?
-What's going on? -Leave us alone.
发生了什么事?别来烦我们
We're just talking.
我们只是在聊天
-We don't need you talking to her. -Leave us alone.
我们不需要你来跟她聊天D走开
We're just talking.
我们只是在聊天
This nigger's trying to pick up on Barbara.
这个黑鬼想要勾搭巴巴拉
l don't need trouble. Just being polite.
我不想惹麻烦请礼貌一点
No, you're not. You're talking about the ocean.
才不是．我们只是在聊大海
-What do you want? -What's going on?
D你想要干什么?D发生了什么事?
What do you want?
你们想要干什么?
What do l want?
我想要干什么?
l wanna see your brains.
我要你脑袋开花
Run!
快跑
Sorry.
对不起
-l'm sorry. l didn't mean it. -You're sorry?
对不起．我不是故意的你在道歉吗?
-Sorry enough? -Yes, sir.
D道歉就可以了吗?是的，先生
Yeah?
是的?
Then prove it.
那么你证明给我看
Come on, prove it. Show him.
快点，证明给他看
Get down on your knees.
跪下
Suck his peter, you son of a bitch!
舔他的小弟弟你这个狗娘养的
l think he's got the point.
我想他已经得到教训了
-Go on. -He's got the point!
“决点他已经受到教训了
Do it! l'll kill you. l'll blow your brains out.
照我的话做 否则我杀了你我会让你的脑袋开花
Don't shoot me, please.
求求你，别开枪
Go on.
做啊
快点
Son of a gun, you're gonna do it, aren't you?
狗娘养的，你不做，是吧?
Sick bastard.
兔急子
Oh, no, my eye!
哦，不，我的眼睛
Get out!
滚
-You call the cops, l'll kill you! -Hurry up, man. Come on!
如果你报警，我就宰了你开点，伙计，我们快点
l don't think they'd call the cops, but we better get out of here.
我想他们不会报警的但是我们最好快点离开这里
What do you got?
你打听到了什么消息?
No harm will come to that girl because of me?
那个女孩不会因为我受到伤害吧‘
Carter says he wants to live happily ever after with her.
卡特说他要跟她过的比以前过的豆幸福
What you got?
你打听到了什么?
-She was with a man named Frank Green. -Hang on. Where?
她现在跟一个叫弗兰克“格林
男人在一起继续说他们在哪?
Skylar Apartments. Skylar and 83rd.
云雀公寓．云雀路83号
Frank Green. What do you know about this guy?
弗兰克“格林．你知道这个家伙吗
He's a gangster. Hijacks liquor and cigarettes. Good with a knife.
一个强盗．专门抢劫酒和烟草很善于玩刀
-Seen him in action? -No, l just heard about him.
D你看过他抢劫吗?没有，只是听说过
Here's another 1 00.
这里是100美金
l'll be calling you again.
我会再打电话给你
Mr. Rawlins, l'm Detective Miller.
罗林斯先生我是米勒探长
Mason. Hands on the car.
马森．开车
-Come with us. -Where?
请跟我们来D去哪?
-You'll see. -Why am l arrested?
D你去了就知道你们为什么要逮捕我
-You'll see. -l got a right to know why.
D你去了就知道我有权知道愿意
You got a right to fall down, break your face and come with me.
你也有权摔破脸以后再跟我们走
-You got him? -Got him coming home.
D你们抓到他了?他刚回到家就抓到他了
Ezekiel Rawlins. You can take those cuffs off if you cooperate.
伊泽科尔．g林斯．如果你合作的话我们就会把那个手拷解下
-Yes, sir, l'm cooperating. -Turn around.
是的，长官．我会合作的转过去
Sit over there. Sit down.
坐在那儿．坐下
Where were you this morning about 5 a.m.?
今天早上5点的时候你在哪里?
What?
什么?
He means this morning!
他是说今天早上
l was out drinking. l carried a friend into his house.
我出去喝酒了．我送一个朋友回家
l don't know. l didn't look at a clock.
我不知道．我没有看时间
You were drinking at 89th and Central, illegal club called John's.
你们在市中心大街89号，一家叫约翰的非法经营的酒家喝酒
Answer. You got a lot bigger troubles than an illegal bar.
回答．你现在遇到的麻烦比去非法酒吧大多了
-What you talking about? -We're talking about...
D你在说什么?我们在说．．．
...taking your black ass out and putting a bullet in your head.
把你这个黑蠢驴带出来给你一枪让你脑袋开花
Sit down.
坐下
When did you leave Coretta James' house?
你是什么时候离开克拉塔“琼斯的房子?
Around 5:30, l guess.
5：30左右，我猜
-Did you go back later? -No, sir, l did not.
D你之后又回去了吗?D没有，长官
Did you and Dupree have words over Miss James?
你和杜瑞因为琼斯小姐吵架了吗?
-Words? -You heard him!
D吵架?你被他他听到了
Did you two argue over Coretta?
你们因为克拉塔吵架了吗?
-Did you? -No, we didn't argue about nothing!
D有吗?没有我们没有因为任何事情吵架
-He was asleep! -She went to sleep too.
D他那时候睡着了D她也睡着了
But she won't wake up.
但是她永远都不会醒来
-Where did you go when you left? -Wait.
D你离开以后又去了哪里?D等等
She won't wake up?
她再也不会醒过来了?
-Where'd you go? -l don't know! l had a hangover!
D你去了哪里?我不知道 我那时候感到宿醉
-You had a hangover. -l went home!
D你感到宿醉D我会家了
That explains everything.
那一切都得到解释了
He had a hangover.
他因为喝酒而感到宿醉
Back off!
后退
Back off! Back off!
后退 后退
Get out of here!
出去
Let's go! Get out of here!
开点 出去
Come on, you son of a bitch!
过来，你这个狗娘养的
Calm down!
冷静
You son of a bitch.
你这个兔急子
They left me alone in that musty room for 3 hours...
他们把我留在那个发霉的房间3小时以后
... till some guy in a suit about two sizes too big said I could go.
直到有一个穿着比自己个子
大两个码的西装的家伙来跟我说我可以走了
The game of cops and niggers kept up outside, but I hardly noticed.
警察和黑鬼的游戏还在继续而我居然没有察党
I had seen dead bodies before.
我以前看过尸体
Cold, hard...
冷冷，很生硬
...still as concrete...
一动不动就好像水泥一样．
... eyes wide open, staring up at nothing.
还睁着眼睛没有焦距
But not Coretta.
但是克拉塔不会这样的．
I could still feel her heartbeat.
我现在还能够感觉到他的心跳声
Hey, Ezekiel Rawlins.
嘿，伊泽科尔．g林斯
Somebody in the back would like to talk to you.
坐在车子后座的人想跟你谈一谈
l ain't got time.
我没有时间
Get in. We'll take you.
上车．否则我们会带上车
My boss wants to talk to you about Coretta James.
我的老板想跟你谈一谈克拉塔“琼斯的事
lf he wanted to hurt you, it would've happened already.
如果他想要对你不利的话早就下手了
Come on.
快点
Get in.
上车
Go up front and sit with Norman.
到前面去跟诺曼一起坐
Give me a kiss.
亲我一下
That's my adopted son, Jesus.
那是我的养子，杰西
l can see the police roughed you up a bit.
我可以看到警察对你很粗景
That's a practice of theirs that has to change.
他们这种作法真的得好好的改一改
That has to change.
“定要好好改一改
She was beaten...
她被殴打
...and died of a heavy blow to the back of the head.
后脑勺重重的D击要了她的命
l suppose you know that.
我以为你知道
No, l didn't, Mr. Terell.
不，我不知道特瑞尔先生
-You know who l am? -l read the newspapers.
D你知道我是谁?D我看过报纸
You're running for mayor against Carter.
你和卡特一起竞选市长
l am the next mayor, Mr. Rawlins.
我就是下一任的市长罗林斯先生
And, luckily for you, a friend of the Negro.
而，你很幸运一个黑人的朋友
Coretta worked a while for me.
克拉塔普经为我工作
She answered phones at my campaign office on 1 03rd and Western.
她在我在西方大街103号竞选办公室负责帮我接电话
So when l heard that the police had a suspect...
所以当我听到警察已经找到嫌疑犯．．．
...l got out of bed immediately because of my concern.
我就马上起床了．因为我很关心这个
Was there anyone with you, Mr. Rawlins?
有没有其它人和你在一起罗林斯先生?
Anyone besides Mr. Dupree Brouchard?
除了杜瑞．t自切尔以外的其它人?
No, sir.
没有，先生
A young lady named Daphne Monet, perhaps?
也许是一个叫望芜摩耐特年轻女土
Nobody.
没有其它人
Of course not. Why would....
当然没有．为什么会
Why would you tell someone whom you've only just met?
你怎么会把事情告诉一个你刚刚认识的人呢?
You can trust me.
你可以相信我
There was nobody else there.
那里没有其它人
l believe you.
我相信你
-Can we drop you off? -No.
我们可以送你回去吗?不用了
l'll get out here.
我会在这里下车
-This must be quite out of your way. -No, it's okay.
D这里离你的家一定很远不，没关系
May l offer you cab fare?
你要坐出租车的钱吗?
-No, thank you. -Are you sure?
“不用了，谢谢你确定吗?
lt's okay.
可以了
You're hitting my spot, baby.
操我，宝贝
Daphne asleep by now, so....
望芜已经睡着了所以．．．
Go around here telling everybody ''Dahlia. ''
在这里到处打听望而尔”
Coloured women ain't good enough for you no more?
有色人种的女人已经不能满足你的胃口了吗
All you doing is nosing after my friend.
你只想要打听关于我的朋友的消息
Coloured women ain't good enough for you no more?
有色人种的女人已经不能满足你的胃口了吗
Is this Mr. Rawlins?
是罗林斯先生吗?
Who's this?
是谁?
This is Daphne Monet.
我是望芜摩耐特
-You're looking for me. -Who told you that?
D你在拢我是谁告诉你的?
You know who told me.
你知道是谁告诉我的
Coretta.
克拉塔
She was found murdered this morning.
今天早上发现她被谋杀了
I don't know what I should do.
我不知道我该怎么做
Do you care to talk to me alone, or should I call the police?
你介意跟我单独谈一谈吗或者是我该报警?
Ain't no reason to call the police.
你没有理由报誓
Then come over and explain yourself to me.
那么你过来这里亲自跟我解释
I'm at the Ambassador Hotel.
我现在在大使酒店
This part of the hotel is white-only.
这家酒店只允许白人进入
So go to the side entrance, and the bellboy will sneak you up.
所以你从侧门进来”1通会偷偷带你上来
Hello, Mr. Rawlins.
你好，罗林斯先生
Hello, Miss Monet.
你好，摩耐特小姐
Should l think of you as a friend of Coretta's or a private dick?
我应该是把你当成是克拉塔的朋友呢
还是一个私家侦探?
Well, l ain't no detective.
喂，我不是探长
l was just hired by a fella that works for Todd Carter.
我只是受聘于一个为托普“卡特工作的家伙
l had to pay Coretta not to tell you where l was.
我不得不付钱让克拉塔别告诉你我在哪
She got you too.
她收了你的钱
She definitely gave me the wrong address.
那她肯定把错误的地址给我
-Where'd she say l was? -Said you was in Watts.
D她说我在哪里?她说你在瓦特大街
At the Skylar Apartments with a fella named Frank Green.
在云雀公寓和一个叫弗兰克“格林家伙在一起
What else did she tell you?
她还告诉了你什么?
l don't know. What else is there?
我不知道．还有什么?
Nothing.
没有
l make no apology for my feelings for Frank. He's very dear to me.
我无需为弗兰克而感到抱歉他对于我来说很重要
Bourbon?
波夯威士忌酒?
Please, straight up.
求你，说真话
How well did you know Coretta?
你有多了解克拉塔?
She was a very close friend.
她是我一个很亲密的朋友
Maybe you know why she got killed?
你也许知道为什么她会被谋杀
Why would l know that?
我为什么会知道?
She was your friend. She knew about you and Frank.
她是你的朋友．她知道你和弗兰克的事
Maybe somebody wanted to keep that secret.
也许有人想要守住这个秘密
-Mr. Rawlins, if you think-- -Easy. You can call me Easy.
罗林斯先生，如果你认为伊斯．你可以叫我伊斯
Easy, if you think Frank killed Coretta...
伊斯，如果你认为是弗兰克杀死克拉塔．
...you don't know very much about him.
是因为你不了解他
Frank doesn't beat people up. He prefers to use a knife as his weapon.
弗兰克从来不动手打人他情愿用刀子做武器
What do you prefer as your weapon?
那你用什么做武器?
Why not search me and find out?
为什么不来我身上按一按?
Mind if l have another drink?
介意我再唱一杯吗?
Help yourself.
请自便
-Listen, Mr. Rawlins-- -Easy.
忻着罗林斯先生D伊斯
Easy...
伊斯
...l called to ask you to drive me to Todd's house.
我打电话给你是想请你开车送我去托普的房子
Pardon?
你说什么?
You found me. Now l want you to take me to Todd Carter's.
你找到我了．我现在要你带我去托普卡特那儿
Call Todd Carter. Have him send for you.
打电话给托普“卡特让他派人来接你
l have to go someplace else on the way.
我顺路还想去别的地方
Someplace l don't want Todd to know about.
我不让托普知道我去的地方
There's a man named Richard McGee.
有一个人叫里查“麦墓
He lives up in Laurel Canyon.
他住在劳雷尔峡谷
He delivered a letter of mine to the wrong place...
他把我的一封信送错了地方
...and l must get it back.
我得拿回来
At 4:00 in the morning?
在凌晨4：00?
lmportant letter.
这封信很重要
Yes, it is.
没错
But l need to go there before l go to Todd's.
我去托普家以前一定得去那儿
l'll pay you.
我会付你钱
When did you talk to Coretta?
你什么时候跟克拉塔交谈的?
l don't know, 7:30, 8:00, l guess.
我不知道，7：30，8：00，我猜
Listen, Easy, l don't want...
听着，伊斯，我不想
...to talk about Coretta now.
现在谈克拉塔的事
Did you go to her house?
你去过她的房子吗?
No.
没有
She called me.
她打电话给我
She was in a good mood.
那时候她的心情很好
She always....
她总是
l didn't mean to upset you, Daphne.
我并不想让你伤心，望芜
But you understand that...
但是你要明白
...you was the last one to talk to her before she got killed.
你是她临死前最后一个跟她交谈的人
l don't mean to upset you...
我并不是想让你伤心
...but as far as l know, you were the last one to see her.
但是据我所知你是最后一个见她的人
Now, where does that leave us?
离开我们去哪?
All right, change out of that housecoat. l'll carry you.
好的，你去把家常服换了我载你去
Are you nervous?
你很紧张吗?
Nervous? Here I was...
紧张?现在我
...at night, in a white neighbourhood with a white woman.
深夜，和一个白人女人在白人的住宅区里
I wasn't nervous.
我不是紧张
I was stupid.
我是愚磊
Make a left up here.
在这儿左转
Getting Daphne back to Todd Carter suddenly didn't seem so easy.
带望芜回去见托普“卡特突然间变得不再那么简单
Who was this guy Richard McGee?
里查“麦墓是谁?
Just park behind that car.
悖在那辆车的后面就可以了
Oh, my God!
我，天啊
-Who's that at the door? -lt's him.
谁在那扇门的旁边?D是他
You fought in Europe?
你在欧洲打过仗?
What you doing in my house?
你们在我的屋子里干什么?
What happened to your head?
你的头是怎么了?
What you doing in my house? You got no right to break into my house!
你们在我的屋子里干什么?
你们没有权力破门而入跑进我的房子里
Where have you been?
你去哪了?
l went to see a girl. Why? You don't get none?
我去见一个女孩了．干吗你不了解吗?
l didn't come here to play, nigger.
黑鬼，我不是来这玩的
That's my money in your pocket.
你的口袋里装的是我的钱
We've been by the address you gave me on Frank.
我们去过你给我们的弗兰克的地址
But he moved from there.
但是他已经搬走了
A year ago.
“年以前
What do you want me to do? l'll give you the money--
你要我怎么做?我会给你钱
Do you believe in God?
你相信上帝吗?
l'm curious if pain's any different for a religious man.
我真的很好奇相信上帝的人会不会有不同的痛苦
-l'll show you what l do to liars. -l seen her.
D我会让你看看我是怎么对付撒谎的人我见过她
Where?
在哪里?
Come on.
快说
She called me. l carried her up to the Hollywood Hills.
她打电话给我．我开车送她到好莱坞小山丘上
-Where's she now? -She took off.
她现在在哪里?她跑掉了
Bullshit. Where is she?
胡说．她在哪?
She took off.
她跑掉了
While l was looking at the dead man, she took off.
在我看着那个男人的尸体的时候，她就跑掉了
Come on in.
进来
Sit down.
坐下
What'd she do? Take his car?
她那时候做了什么开走了他的车?
McGee.
麦墓
Write down where you picked her up.
写下你去接她的地址
Write it down!
写
This bologna is stuck in my molar.
这条大腊肠把我的牙缝塞住了
l get that with popcorn.
我用那个跟爆米花一起吃
Get me some whiskey.
给我点威士忌
lt's in the cabinet. You get it your damn self.
就在橱柜里．该死的，你自己拿
He's got balls, you gotta give him that.
他想要玩花样你就陪他玩玩
Shoot him.
射他
l'm just kidding.
我只是开个玩笑
Easy, you're a brave man.
伊斯你是勇敢的男人
l need brave men working for me.
我需要勇敢的男人为我工作
You do a nice job too.
你也干得很好
Get me a whiskey.
给我一点威士忌
Find Frank Green. He'll lead us to her.
把弗兰克“格林拢出来他会帮我们找到她
No, thank you.
不，谢谢
Too many people getting killed around me already.
我的身边已经有多人被谋杀了
You're connectible to two murders.
你已经卷入两宗谋杀案里了
You're gonna do whatever l tell you to do.
你得照着我的话去做
You find him. l'll be checking in.
你去找到他．我会查的
That's some cheap shit. Let's go.
该死的便宜货．我们走吧
Since Albright liked surprise parties...
既然奥尔布赖特喜欢开惊喜派对．
...I had a friend of my own I wanted to invite.
我也有一个自己朋友可以邀请来参加这个游戏
I placed a call to Etta Mae Alexander in Houston.
我打了个电话给在休斯顿的埃特“梅“亚历山大
I gave her a message for her husband...
我请她帮我留言给她的丈夫．．．
...Mouse.
麦斯
Cast your vote on June 1 1 for Matthew Terell.
请你在6月11日来投马太?特瑞一票
That girl called me last night.
那个女孩昨天晚上打电话给我
What girl?
什么女孩?
The one your friend Albright is looking for.
就是你的朋友奥尔布赖特要拢的女孩
-That's lucky. -lt wasn't no luck. lt was you.
D你很幸运根本就不是幸运．是你对吧
Only you and Coretta had my number and knew l was looking for the girl.
只有你和克拉塔有我的电话号码也只有你侗知道我在拢她
Coretta was too busy scamming Daphne.
而克拉塔忙着返骗望芜
-lt was you. -Maybe she looked in the phone book.
D是你可能她是从电话本上找到的
l ain't in the book. l thought you was my friend.
电话本上根本就没有我的电话枉我还将你当成我的朋友
Why didn't you tell him where she was?
你为什么不告诉他她在哪?
What the hell you mean, looking all ugly like you'll do something?
该死的，你到底是什么意恩
我也会跟你一样做那些见不得人的事吗
l think l'll do something.
我想我现在就该做点坏事
Stop that shit!
别胡说了
That's my marble! My uncle left me that after he died!
那是我的大理石台 我叔叔死后留给我的
Goddamn it, he's about to get it back.
该死的他现在可以把它收回去了
-Let's talk. -Talk!
我们谈一谈D谈
What you got me into?
你为什么要把我卷进去?
l told her Albright was looking for her.
我告诉她奥尔布赖特在拢她
l figured l'd help you make a few dollars and throw Albright off!
我以为我可以帮你晚点钱顺便把奥尔布赖特甩掉
She wanted to know about you. l gave her your number.
她想要了解你．我就把你的电话给她
-Where's she at? -l don't know!
她现在在哪?D我不知道
Don't lie to me!
别骗我
l'm not lying to you!
我没有撒谎
-What's she running from, then? -She didn't tell me.
D那她为什么要逃?她没有告诉我
Easy, look at me. l am your friend!
伊斯，看着我．我是你的朋友
l didn't mean to get you in no trouble.
我不是故意让你卷进麻烦里的
Look, you seen her.
听着，你见过她了
l mean, she is something else, man.
我是说她并不是那么简单的，伙计
You know what l'm saying?
你知道我的意思吗?
Oh, Joppy....
哦，佐皮
What?
什么?
Like Albright said, ''When you're mixed up in something...
就像奥尔布赖特说的当你卷进麻烦事里的时候
...you better be mixed up to the top. ''
你最好占据主导的地位
So that's where I was going.
而那就是我要做的
All the way to the top.
尽量占据主导地位
Everybody was peeing on my head and telling me it was rain.
每个人都对着我的脸撒尿并告诉我这是下雨
Guess they figured I was some new kind of fool, and maybe I was.
以为我是一个傻瓜也许我真的是一个傻瓜
I was ready to start fighting back.
我要开始还击了
I believed somehow that I could live through this bad dream...
我相信我一定可以在这个歪梦里熬过去的．
...about pretty girls and gangsters...
一个有漂亮女孩，强盗
...and standing face-to-face with the richest man in town.
还有面对城里最有钱的富翁的恶梦
May l help you?
请我有什么事?
-l'm looking for Mr. Carter. -l'm sorry, he's a very busy man.
“我是来拢卡特先生我很抱歉，他很忙
Too busy to hear about that chippy of his that dumped him?
忙得连听听一个普经跟他风花雪月
Excuse me.
对不起
-Mr.--? -Rawlins.
D你是?D罗林斯
Why don't you come with me, sir?
先生请跟我来好吗?
lt's not smart talking about Carter's business to a secretary.
跟一个秘书谈卡特先生的私事是很不明智的
There's too much going on...
我没有时间
...for me to give a damn about what you think is smart.
认真考虑你认为的该死的明智作法
Wait here, Mr. Rawlins.
请在这里等一下罗林斯先生
Mr. Carter will see you.
卡特想见见你
Mr. Rawlins.
罗林斯先生
Mr. Carter.
卡特先生
You've heard from Daphne?
你见过望芜?
Yeah, last night.
是的，就在昨天晚上
She's still in town?
她还在城里?
She was last night.
她昨天晚上还在
And what did she say?
她说了什么?
What was she wearing?
她穿着怎样的衣服?
Blue dress, high heels.
蓝色裙子，还有高跟鞋
That's her.
就是她
Would you like to come in?
进来谈谈好吗?
Please.
请吧
-Have a seat. -Thank you.
坐谢请谢
-l want some answers. -Would you like a brandy?
D我要知道答案你唱白兰地吗?
l wanna know what l got myself into.
我要知道我到底卷进了什么是非
Pardon?
你说什么?
l wanna know the real reason Mr. Albright hired me.
我要知道奥尔布赖特先生雇佣我的真正原因
Mr. Albright?
奥尔布赖特先生?
Yeah, the man you hired to find Daphne.
没错，就是你请来拢望芜的男人
l think there's been a mistake here.
我想这其中有误会
Who are you talking about?
你在说什么?
Wait a minute.
等一下
You didn't hire somebody to find your girl?
你没有请人去找你的女朋友吗?
Of course not.
当然没有
Until just now, l thought she was hundreds of miles away from here.
直到刚才我还以外她在数百英里以外
You say someone's looking for her?
你说有人在到处拢她?
Someone's looking for her.
有人在拢她
Nothing personal, but what's going on between y'all?
我不是要管你的私事但是你们之间到底是发生了什么
Nothing.
没事
We were going to get married.
我们打算要结婚的
We had a fight, and it is really none of your concern.
我们吵架了但这不管你的事
So someone's after her.
那么是有人在拢她要对她不利
Mr. Albright.
奥尔布赖特先生
-And he says l'm his employer. -Ever heard of Richard McGee?
而且他说是我雇佣他的你知道里查“麦墓吗?
Who?
说?
Look, l....
听着，我
-Why would somebody be after her? -Can you find her again?
D为什么有人要追踪她呢?你可以再一次找到她吗?
lt's important...
这很重要
...for her sake.
看在她的份上
l'm willing to pay you.
我会付你钱
Why did she leave?
她为什么要离开?
lt's really none of your concern, but l'll pay you to find her.
这真的与你无关，但是如果你找到她我会给你钱
$1 000.
1000美金
$1 000?
1000美金?
l'll take $200 right now.
我现在就要200美金
You're trying to take advantage of me.
你现在算是在打劫我
Let me inform you of something.
让我告诉你
The incumbent mayor, the chief of police, close friends of mine.
现任的市长，警察局长都是我的好朋友
They eat at my house regularly.
他们经常来我家吃饭
That's good. Then they can help us find her.
那很好他们可以帮你找到她
No, they can't.
不，他们不行
l'll have Baxter write you out a check.
我会让巴斯特写张支票给你
Why you stop running for mayor?
为什么你要停止竞选市长?
-Baxter will write you a check. -Why's Terell looking for Daphne?
D巴斯特会给你支票为什么特瑞要拢望芜
Baxter will write you a check.
巴斯特会给你支票
l'll take cash.
我只要现金
Here, take it all. Just take it all.
给你，拿去．统统都拿去
l'll be in touch, Mr. Carter.
我会跟你保持联系卡特先生
So Albright had lied to me.
所以奥尔布赖特对我撒谎了
Instead of working for Carter, he worked for Terell...
他不是为卡特工作而是特瑞．．．
... the man running for mayor against Carter.
而这个人是卡特的竞选对手
And they was all throwing money my way...
而他们全都把钱扔给我
... to find the girl in the blue dress.
只为了找到一个穿蓝色裙子的女孩
I knew her boyfriend Frank Green hijacked trucks hauling liquor...
我知道她的男朋友弗兰克“格林打劫了一辆装满酒的卡车．．．
...and sold it at half-price to places down on Central Avenue.
而且以半价卖给了中心大街的一家店
So I decided to kick up some dust right in Frank's back yard.
所以我打算在弗兰克后院放火
Mr. Rawlins, what were you saying?
罗林斯先生你在说什么?
Frank Green.
弗兰克“格林
-Who? -l'm looking for him.
一谁?我在拢他
-l don't know. -Why you treat me like this?
D我不知道为什么你这样对我
-l don't know any Frank Green. -You don't know Frank?
我不认识什么弗兰克“格林你不认识弗兰克?
You know me though, don't you?
但是你认识我，是吗?
My man Frank Green told me to talk to you.
我的朋友弗兰克“格林告诉我让我跟你谈
-He said to talk to you. -Who is that?
D他说跟你谈一谈D他是谁?
What do you mean, ''Who is that?'' He told me to talk to you.
你在说什么，“谁是谁”他叫我来跟你谈的
Come on. Give me something.
好的．给我一点东西
All right, give me a beer.
好的，给我一杯啤酒
Can l get a beer? Can l get a beer?
我可以要杯啤酒吗我可以吗?
Thank you.
损4谢
Wait. Frank Green told me you'd have pints for me.
等等．弗兰克“格林告诉我你会给我好几品脱
Who's Frank Green?
谁是弗兰克“格林?
-You know who Frank Green is. -Al, talk to this man.
D你知道谁是弗兰克“格林奥尔，你来跟这个男人说
-You know Frank. -What are you talking about?
D你认识弗兰克你在说什么?
You don't know Frank?
你不认识弗兰克?
-l don't. -Let's get him on the phone.
D不认识我们大电话给他
Don't need my trees trimmed.
我的树不需要砍
There's a man!
小心你后面的男人
Damn! Frank, wait a minute!
该死的 弗兰克，等一下
Hold it! Let's talk!
把你的刀子放下我们来谈一谈
Let's talk.
我们来谈一谈
Wait a minute! l got $500 for you, Frank.
等一下 我给你500美元，弗兰克
Rich white man wants--
一个有钱的白人男人
Goddamn it!
该死的
Want me to shoot him?
你要我开枪吗?
-Mouse! -Want me to shoot him?
D麦斯 D你要我开枪吗?
lt's all right.
没关系
What the hell is happening, man?
伙计，该死的到底发生了什么事?
l'll blow your nose off.
我会把你的昌梁打断
Don't shoot him!
别开枪
Where's Daphne Monet, Frank?
望芜．摩耐特在哪里弗兰克?
Maybe you don't know where she is...
也许你不知道她在哪
...but we can help each other find her.
我们可以互相帮助一起拢她
-You heard him. -Mouse, no!
D你来听?麦斯，不
-Rawlins residence. -Sit down.
罗林斯家
He busy right now. You gonna have to call back.
他现在很忙．你稍后再打
A rich man is willing to pay $1 000 just to talk to this girl.
一个有钱男人愿意出1000美金只为了跟这个女孩说几句话
$1 000! That's a hell of a lot of money, man!
1000美元 该死那真是个不小的数目，伙计
Wait, wait. Wait a minute.
等等，等等．等一下
Let me try.
让我来试试
Look here-- lt's Frank, right?
听着D叫弗兰克，对吧?
Let go of me, man! Let go of me!
听我说，伙计 听我说
Damn it!
该死的
Don't you ever grab me when l got a gun in my hand!
我手上拿着枪的时候别来抓我
Shit!
妈的
You got blood on my coat.
你把血弄到我的衣服上了
lt's a damn expensive coat.
这衣服该死的很责
Where's your bathroom at, man?
伙计，你的洗手间在哪?
We gotta find that girl and get that money.
我们要找到那个女孩拿到钱
No, we don't have to go find nobody!
不，我们谁也不拢了
l done changed my mind. l don't need your kind of help.
我改变主意了．我不需要你帮忙了
Man cut a damn smile in your neck, you tell me you don't need my help.
那个家伙让你的脖子上开花你居然说不需要我的帮忙
You pulled this shit 5 years ago when you killed Navrochet.
5年前你不是就干这种勾当让诺勒切脑袋开化的吗?
You ain't been here 5 minutes, you shot somebody already.
你来到这里还不够5分钟你就对人开枪
Come on, Easy.
好了，伊斯
-Cut me in on this thing, man. -No.
D这件事算上我的一份伙计D不
Easy, l'm trying to do right.
伊斯，我只是想把事情做好
l mean, you know, now.
我的意思是你知道的，现在
l could help you. You'll need somebody at your back.
我可以帮助你．你需要有人在后面掩护你
-l'll let you run the show. -You'll let me run the show?
D我让你当主角．D你让我当主角?
l won't do nothing you don't tell me to do.
我会照你说的去做
You're gonna let me run the show?
你让我做主角?
You'll do what l say?
你会听我的?
l'm gonna do everything you say.
我一切都听你的
That's the wrong hand, Mouse.
不是那只手，麦斯
Boy, how you been?
伙计，你过的怎样?
-Who was that on the phone? -l don't know, man.
．Rlj才打电话来的是谁?我不知道，伙计
Sounded like some white girl.
听起来像一个白人女孩的声吉
Ezekiel. Came to ask you a few more questions.
伊泽科尔．我们是来问你几个问题
-Why don't you invite us in? -l'll come out.
为什么不请我们进去?我会出来
What happened?
什么事?
l don't remember doing that to your neck.
我记得我没有刮破你的脖子
What do you know about Richard McGee?
你知道里查“麦墓的什么事?
A dead white man in Laurel Canyon.
一个在劳雷尔峡谷死亡的男人
He has a note in his pocket with '' Coretta James'' written on it.
他的口袋中里有一张写着克拉塔“琼斯的纸条
You feel more talkative?
你没有话要说吗?
l'll bet six bits to a bottle of piss we're looking at a double.
我赌他妈的俯尿你有问题
lf we place you in the dead man's house.
如果我们假设你去过死者的家
l wasn't in no dead man's house.
我没有去过任何一个死人的家
We could go to the station, send a team over here.
我们可以回去警察局派一个小队的警察过来
They'll find something that will place you at that house.
他们会查出你为什么要去死者的家
Evidence has a funny way of showing up.
证据就会神奇地出现
You ain't got nothing on me, because l ain't done nothing.
你们不肯能找到任何证据因为我什么也没做
We know you know a lot more.
我们知道你知道更多的事情
Tell us everything you know...
把你知道的东西全都告诉我们．．．
...or you're going down for both murders.
还是你要顶上杀死两个人的罪名
-l don't know nothing. -Sure you do.
我什么也不知道你当然知道
-Let's go. -All right, look.
“好的，听着
-Give me more time. -Forget it.
“再给我一点时间一没门
Give me till tomorrow morning. Maybe l can dig something up.
等我到明天早上．也许我可以查出更多的事情
What do you think? We could do that.
你认为怎样?我可以答应
Take the cuffs off.
把手拷解下来
You got till tomorrow morning.
我们可以等到明天早上
Have a nice evening, Ezekiel.
有一个愉快的晚上伊泽科尔
I played along, just like the cops wanted me to.
我一个人去查，就像那些警察要的那样
It was a game to them.
这是他们的游戏
But they'd play for keeps tomorrow because a white man was dead now.
但是他们一定要拢个替死鬼因为有一个白人死了
Guilty or not, somebody was gonna have to pay for this one.
不管有没有罪“定要有人顶这个罪名
ls Dupree's sister's house off Compton Boulevard or Avenue?
离康普敦大道不远的是杜瑞姐姐的房子吗?
-We're going somewhere else first. -Did that girl call?
D我们得先去别的地方那个女孩有再打电话来吗
We going to see her?
我们去见她吗?
No.
-l see them people giving you trouble. -l ain't got time.
我要去见那些拢你麻烦的人我没有时间
-Leave my trees alone! -You got too many.
D离我的树远点 你已经有很多了
-l'll knock down a couple for you. -Leave my trees alone!
我会帮你砍掉一两颗别动我的树
Tell me what you think when you get back, all right?
你回来的时候告诉我你考虑地怎样，好吗
-Who's there? -Easy.
D伊斯
-What you want? -Let me in.
D你要干什么?让我进去
l got no time to be fooling with you. l'm sleeping.
我没有时日跟你玩愚蠢的游戏我要睡党
Open this door. Act like you got some sense.
开门．如果你识相的话
Mouse.
麦斯
Get out the way, fool. We ain't got all day.
蠢材，别挡路．我们不会呆很久
Have a seat.
坐
-Y'all want a beer? -Sure. Thank you.
D你们要唱点啤酒吗?D当然，谢谢
What you smoking, Junior? Zapattas?
你抽的是什么牌子的香烟姐尼尔?赞帕塔?
-This one's yours too. -l don't know.
D这个也是你的我不知道
You killed McGee.
是你杀了麦墓
What you talking about?
你在说什么?
No time to play. l know you killed him.
我没有时日跟你耍花样我知道是你杀了他
-You crazy, man! -Sit down.
D伙计，你疯了D坐下
-Tell me. -What you talking about?
D告诉我你在说什么
The police will, when they find your prints in his house.
警察很快就会知道，当他们在他的房子里发现了你的指纹的时候
Fingerprints?
指纹?
Hattie had you pull that man out of John's that night.
海提那天晚上让你不那个男人赶出约翰酒吧的时候
He was laying dead in the same suit and a bullet in his head.
他死的时候就是穿着那间衣服，头上还有子弹
l ain't killed nobody!
我没有杀人
Quit lying, you thick-headed, cornbread-eating--
别撒谎了，你这个这不知羞耻的大草包
Sit down, Junior.
坐下，姐尼尔
Sit down, now.
现在，坐下
Tell me, and maybe l'll forget what l know.
告诉我，也许我会把我知道的事情忘掉
Or l'll tell Mouse to shoot you.
要不然我会叫麦斯开枪杀你
You killed that man and took his money.
你杀死那个男人然后拿走了他的钱
-l don't know who you talking about! -You had to rob him!
我不知道你在说什么你不得不抢劫他
l didn't touch nothing in that man's house!
我没有动那个男人房间里的任何东西
Goddamn.
该死的
Sit down.
坐下
Hattie had me take him out to his car.
海蒂让我把他从车上揪出来
He was so drunk he gave me $1 0 just to drive him home.
他唱醉了，他给我10美金开车送他回家
-l know you took that. -Hell, yeah.
我知道你拿了该死的，是的
Then he asked about that white girl you asked about.
然后他问起了你打听的那个白人女孩
l told him l seen her with Coretta. What the hell l care?
我告诉他我看见她跟克拉塔在
You tell him, but not me?
你告诉他，却不告诉我?
l don't like your ass. And he give me $50.
我不喜欢你这个混蛋．而且他给了我50美金
Just to tell him you saw her with Coretta?
只是告诉他你看见她和克拉塔在一起吗
To deliver a letter.
帮他送信
l give it to Coretta to give to her the next morning.
第二天早上我把它交给了克拉塔
You better be telling the truth.
你最好说实话
Come on, let's go.
l'm telling the truth. l ain't killed nobody.
我说的是实话．我不想被杀掉
That man was alive when l left. l ain't killed nobody!
我走的时候那个男人还是好好的．我没有杀人
Daphne's letter had worked its way over to the other side of town...
望芜的信已经跑到了城里的另一头去了．．
... to Dupree's sister's house.
到了杜瑞的姐姐的家里
I hoped.
但愿如此
And Junior was innocent, like I knew all along.
是姐尼尔是清白的正如我所料
But I couldn't see no harm in letting the sucker sweat a little bit.
但是我看到了让笨蛋尝到甜头的坏处
-Tried to call you. -Cops just let me out today.
D打电话给我．警察只让我今天出来
My sister's at work. l ain't feel much like talking.
我的妹妹在上班我不想多谈
-Raymond! -Yeah, big man.
D瑞文 是的，大块
ls them pig tails l smell up in there?
我闻到的是猪尾巴的香味吗
Lula Mae made some before work.
露拉“梅上班前弄的
You'll have to excuse me.
我要打扰了
Dupree.
杜瑞
l'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Thank you, Easy.
谢谢你，伊斯
Why somebody wanna kill her like that? lt don't make sense to me.
怎么会有人要杀她呢?我真搞不懂
Did Coretta say anything to you about a letter she was keeping?
克拉塔有没有说什么关于她身上的信的事情?
A letter?
信?
What kind of letter?
什么信?
From that white girl.
一个白人女孩写地信
No.
没有
lt's because of her that Coretta got killed.
就是因为这封信克拉塔才会被杀的
Yeah.
Everything between Daphne and Coretta was always such a damn secret.
望芜和克拉塔的事情总是该死地保持神秘
That old girl...
那个老姑娘
...didn't think nothing about two-timing old Frank.
不要再想出卖朋友的老弗兰克
-You want more tails? -Thanks, Dupree.
D你还要再来一些猪尾巴?D谢谢，杜瑞
She messing around with that guy running for mayor.
她勾搭上了那个竞选市长的家伙
-Todd Carter? -Yeah, that's his name.
D托普“卡特?设错，就是这个人
She probably introduced Coretta to one of them guys.
她可能把克拉塔介绍给他的朋友
He probably came to the house...
他也许去过那间房子
...saw that Coretta wasn't that type of woman.
知道克拉塔并不是那种女人
Cop says she fought him.
警察说她跟他动手打起来了
lmagine that.
想象一下
My baby fought them.
我的宝贝跟他们打起来了
Because she wouldn't have nobody but me.
因为除了我以外她谁也没有
l can't sleep.
我睡不着
l keep seeing her face that morning before l went to work.
那天早上我去上班以前我老是看到她的脸
Junior had just came by the house...
姐尼尔那时候刚刚经过那间房子
...and she come running out carrying her Bible.
然后她拿着她的＜＜圣经＞＞拼命地跑了出来
She say...
她说
...'' Keep this for me, baby.''
宝贝，帮我保管这个
The Bible?
“本《圣经》?
The police won't even let me go near the house.
警察不让我接近她的房子
That's the only thing l got left that belonged to her.
那是她留给我唯一的东西
The Bible.
《圣经》
l knew it was a sign because she's so religious.
我知道这是个信号因为她是多么地虔诚
Oh, God!
哦，上帝
lt's all right, big man.
没事的，大块
-l'm sorry. -That's all right.
我很抱歉D没事的
Get you a drink. Drink this.
唱点酒．把这个给唱了
-All right. Go on now. -That's enough.
“好的．唱吧D够了
Drink that.
唱吧
I was scared now...
我看到的
...and sick from what I saw.
让我感到害，I、6和作呕
Pictures of a much younger Matthew Terell and children.
一个豆年轻的马太“特瑞和小孩
Innocent...
天真
...helpless...
无助
...naked children.
赤裸的小孩
l got it. Let's go.
我找到了．我们走吧
ls you crazy or is you drunk?
你是疯了吗还是唱醉了?
Come on.
快点
Am l drunk?
我醉了吗?
You saw me draw that gun. No man can out-draw me.
你看到我拨出那支枪．没有人可以拨出我的枪
-Put the gun down. -No, l'm drunk.
D把枪放下不，我没有唱醉
l'm drunk. You right.
你说对了．我醉了
l'm gonna put that gun right there.
我会把枪放在那里
l'm gonna see who's drunk.
我要看看到底是谁唱醉了
Now, watch it now. Watch it, goddamn it.
看着这个．看着它，该死的
Right there, now.
现在，就在那
This fool calling me out, he ain't even got no gun.
这个蠢材叫我出去他手里甚至还没有枪
l'll kill that motherfucker.
我会把那个混帐东西杀掉
Let him go.
放了他
Let him live.
放他一条生路
And he'll be scared of you from now on.
从现在开始他就会，I、6了你
He better be scared or l'll kill him.
他最好，I、6了我要不然我会杀了他
He will.
他会的
You better tell him.
你最好告诉他
l will.
我会的
Trust me.
相信我
l'll tell him.
我会告诉他的
Shit.
妈的
Keep an eye on him.
看着他
Where you going?
你要去哪?
The pictures was eating at my pocket like a cigarette burn.
那些照片正在腐蚀我的口袋，就像一根烟头在我的口袋里燃烧一样
Albright killed for those pictures to get them back for Terell.
奥尔布赖特杀人就是为了要帮特瑞拿回那些照片
He killed Richard McGee, who had sold the pictures to Daphne.
他杀了把照片卖给望芜的人里查“麦墓
Time was running out.
时间在不断地流逝
But I had some unfinished business with the girl.
但是我和那个女孩之间还有没有了解的事
She had called earlier, and all I needed was for her to call again.
她较早的时候打过电话来但是我想要她在打一次电话
l'm sorry. l broke into your house.
对不起．我破门而入了
Please don't be angry with me.
请不要生我的气
Now, why should l be angry at you?
现在我为什么要生你的气
May l have a cigarette?
我可以抽根烟吗?
Coretta's boyfriend, Dupree, got out of jail today.
克拉塔的男朋友杜瑞今天出狱了
And you need me to help you find him.
你需要我帮你找到他
l already got the pictures.
我已经那到那些照片了
l paid $7 000 for those pictures. They belong to me.
我花了7000美元买那些照片他们是居于我的
Terell might have something to say about that.
特瑞也许对这些照片也有兴趣
l'll pay you $1 000 for them.
我给你1000美元
-You gave McGee seven. -Then l'll give you seven.
D但是你给麦墓7000那好吧我也给你7000
What does Terell have on you?
到底特瑞抓住了你的什么把柄?
Nothing.
没有
-You want the money or not? -No.
D你到底要不要钱?D不要
l got two murders hanging over me.
我牵涉到两棕谋杀案里面
Unless l find a killer by morning, l'll go to jail.
除非我早天亮以前找到凶手否则的话我就要坐车
-Who killed Coretta? -l don't know.
“是谁杀了克拉塔?我不知道
-She was killed for the pictures? -l don't know.
她是因为那些照片而被杀的吗?我不知道
Frank Green killed her to bring you them pictures.
弗兰克“格林把她杀了帮你拿回那些照片
-No. -Tell it to the police...
D不是的我会把这些告诉警察
...because l ain't taking the rap.
因为我不要做替死鬼
Put the phone down! Put it down!
把电话放下lfg电话放下
Put the phone down!
把电话放下
lt was Frank.
是弗兰克干的吧
-He didn't do it! -Sure he did!
D他没有 就是他干的
You got more than a backdoor romance.
你的秘密情人还不少
He pimped you out to Carter. We're going to the police.
他帮你拉皮条，让你认识卡特我们上警察局去
Why don't you scream, so l can tell the police about your boyfriend!
你为什么不尖叫，那么我就告诉警察你的男朋友的事
Frank is my brother!
弗兰克不是的男朋友
Our mother is Creole. We have different fathers.
我们的妈妈是一个欧洲和非洲的混血儿．我们的父亲不同
Mine is white.
我的父亲是一个白人
That's what Terell has on me.
那就是特瑞抓住的把柄
So far l've been able to keep Frank out of this.
到现在我还在尽量阻止让弗兰克牵涉在内
Who killed Coretta?
是杀了克拉塔?
lt was an accident. She wanted to sell the pictures to Terell.
那只是一个意外．她想要把相片卖给特瑞
Who killed her, goddamn it?
该死的到底是谁把他杀死的?
l asked Joppy to scare her.
我让佐皮去吓唬她
Joppy?
佐皮?
l didn't mean to hurt anybody.
我并不想要伤害任何人
But Todd had to pull out of the election because of me.
但是托普为了我不得不放弃选举
His family really wanted us to get married, but--
他的家里人也想让我们结婚，但是
l'll be a son of a bitch.
你这个兔急子
Get her.
抓住她
Come on.
快点
-Where are the pictures? -l don't know.
照片在哪?D我不知道
Get her in the car.
把他带上车
Come on!
快点
Who we gonna give up to cover this shit?
妈的到底是谁要来负责这件事
I woke up Mouse and told him to drive Dupree's car to 34th and Central.
我把麦斯叫醒，叫他开杜瑞的车到中心大街34号来
It had come to me in less time than it takes to think.:
我没有多余的时候考虑太多的事情
They were taking her someplace more deserted than Albright's office...
他们肯定不会把她带到奥尔布赖特的办公室里
... where there would be no witnesses.
而是到没有人会看见的地方去
And I was being left alive to take the fall.
我一定会活着离开并吸取这次的教训
Give me one of them guns you got.
给我一把枪
Start up my car, keep it hot. l'm coming out fast.
发动我的车，别关上马达我很快就会出来
Let's go.
Let's go. Let's go!
走，走
l'll blow your face off. Let's go!
我会让你的脑袋开火跟我走
Shut up!
闭嘴
-What the hell you doing? -Shut up!
D你这是在干什么?D闭嘴
What is this?
这是什么?
You drive, Mouse.
你来开车，麦斯
Albright's gonna kill the girl.
奥尔布赖特会杀了那个女孩
Now tell me where it is and get it right.
现在你告诉我地点在哪你最好说实话
Get it right, Joppy. Get it right.
说实话，佐皮．说实话
There's a cabin.
有一间小屋
That's all l know. There's a cabin.
我就知道这些有一间小屋
-Where? -lt's in Malibu on Route 9.
D在哪?在玛利布，9路
Make a right turn at the alley.
在前面峡谷转左
This is where he'll be, right?
他就在这，对吧?
-l guess so. -Don't be guessing!
我想是的D不要猜测
He done this kind of thing out there before, so l guess so.
他以前在这里做过这种勾当所以我猜是这样
l thought y'all were friends.
我以外我们都是朋友
He killed Coretta.
他杀了克拉塔
You lying.
你撒谎
l ain't done nothing like that.
我没有做过这种事
Hold on! We need him, Mouse!
住手 我们需要他，麦斯
The girl got $7 000.
那个女孩出7000美元
What?
什么?
The girl offered to pay me $7 000 for them pictures.
那个女孩给我7000美元买回那些照片
Oh, my God!
哦，上帝
Oh, my goodness!
Oh, my God!
哦，天哪
How much further is it?
还可以挖多少?
We coming up on it.
我们挖到宝藏了
There's rope in the trunk. Tie him up.
在车厢里有一条绳子把他绑起来
Yeah, all right.
好的
Man, come on.
伙计，去吧
The girl is lying if she told you l killed that woman.
如果那个女孩说我杀了那个女人，那是她在骗你
Who says she told me?
是谁说是她告诉我的?
l'm gonna shoot him now, okay?
我现在就把他杀了，好吗?
No, don't.
不，不要
Don't shoot.
别杀他
Help me! Help me!
救命 救命
Shut up!
闭嘴
Now, you tell me where the pictures are.
现在，你告诉我那些照片在哪
l don't want to hurt you. Tell me.
我不想伤害你．告诉我
Where are the pictures?
那些照片在哪?
-Easy has them. -You said he had nothing to do with it.
D伊斯拿了你说他跟这个无关
l was lying.
我撒谎了
Lying?
撒谎?
Yeah, you a liar?
是的，你是一个骗子吗?
l know you lie. You lie about being a nigger?
我知道你撒谎．你撒谎说你是黑鬼吗
Tell me the truth.
告诉我实话
What part of you is nigger? Your leg?
你的哪一部分是黑鬼你的腿?
Your arm a nigger? Maybe your face?
你的手?或许是你的脸?
What part of you is nigger?
你的哪一部分是黑鬼?
You know what l'm gonna do?
你知道我会做什么?
Please, no!
求求你，别这样
l'm gonna burn it out of you.
我要把它烧掉，让它脱离你
Easy, is that you?
伊斯，是你吗?
He gone, man.
他跑了，伙计
Gone.
跑了
You all right?
你还好吧?
Can you walk?
还能走路吗?
Come on, let's go.
Where's Joppy?
佐皮在哪?
Where Joppy?
He right there.
就在那
What happened?
发生了什么事?
l ain't had no time to be tying him up.
我还来不急把他帮起来
What?
什么?
You said don't shoot him.
你说了不要开枪杀他
-That's right. -Well, l didn't.
D没错用，我没有
l choked him.
我把他掐死了
What?
什么?
How am l gonna help you out if l'm here fooling around with him?
如果我像傻瓜一样在这里守着他，我怎样帮你?
lf you ain't want him killed, why'd you leave him with me?
如果你不想他被杀掉你为什么把他留给我?
Come on. We got to go, Easy.
快点．我们要走了，伊斯
Easy, come on. Let's go now.
伊斯，快点，我们走吧
Listen...
听着
...what about that dude Frank?
你打算怎样处置那个花花公子弗兰克
-l can run by and kill him before l go. -No, Mouse.
我可以在我走之前把他干掉不，麦斯
You sure?
你确定吗?
Look.
听着
Here's your half.
这里是你的那一半
l know you's too big a fool to take it from her yourself.
我知道你是一个大傻瓜把自己的那一半给回她
lf you need somebody to run them streets with, give me a call.
如果你需要一个人帮你跑肥打电话给我
You know how to put money in a nigger's pocket.
你知道怎样帮黑鬼赚钱
What upset them the most was that l didn't tell them.
我最让他们伤心的就是没有告诉他们
Then Terell threatened to go public about my mother.
然后特瑞威胁说要把我母亲的事公之于众
That just added insult to injury.
那简直就是雪上加霜
When Todd sees the pictures...
当托普看到那些照片的时候
...there'll be nothing in the way of our marriage.
没有什么可以阻止我们结婚
-Are you sure? -Terell doesn't want to go to jail.
D你确定吗?特瑞不想坐车
l'm not talking about Terell.
我不是指特瑞
Todd and l are very much in love, and in the end...
托普和我爱地很深但是结果
...his family just wants him to be happy.
他的家人只想让他高兴
Daphne had gotten the money out of a locker at the YWC A.
望芜从YWcA的保险柜里把钱取了出来
It was money she had gotten from Carter's family.
那是卡特家给她的钱
$30, 000...
30，000美金
... to leave town.
离开这里
She was convinced her Negro blood didn't matter...
他被说服她的黑人血统并不是问题
...now that Terell couldn't use it...
现在特瑞已经不能够在利用这一点了．．
... to keep Carter out of the mayor's race.
让卡特停止竞选市长
She was in love and couldn't see for dreaming...
她坠入爱河却看不到任何梦想
...any better than the rest of us, I guess.
任何比我们其它更好的未来．我猜
Even though we had fought a war to keep the world free...
经营我们为了世界的自由而战斗．．．
... the colour line in America work both ways.
但是美国的种族界限却不受这个制约
Even a rich white man like Todd Carter...
即使是像托普“卡特那样的有钱人
... was afraid to cross it.
也害，I、6逾越这条界限
-Don't walk away. -Damn you!
丹i走开D该死的
Wait.
等等
Please!
求你
Here's the $800 that l owe you.
这是我欠你的800美金
And thank you for protecting her.
谢谢你保护她
You have some pictures.
你还有一些照片
That puts you back in the race.
那就是在竞选中拖你后退的东西
l'll need you to do something for me too.
我也需要你为我做点事
l know.
我知道
You'll have no trouble with the police.
警察不好再拢你的麻烦
lt's a promise.
我答应你
Thank you.
谢谢你
Just so you know...
正如你所知道的
...l do love her.
我真的爱她
You want me to walk you inside?
你要我送你进去吗?
I dropped her off at her brother's...
我开车送他她到他弟弟的家
...a four-plex on Dinker Street.
丁克街4号
She told me her story on the way home...
路上她告诉我她的故事
... like a sinner who wanted to confess.
就像一个罪人在祷告
Her name was Ruby Hanks from Lake Charles, Louisiana.
她的名字叫露比“汉克斯来自路易丝安娜州的查尔斯湖
I suppose all she really wanted was a place to fit in.
我想她只想拢个安身的地方
A few days later, my conscience got the best of me...
几天以后，我的良心又战胜了我的理智．．
...and I went by her place to bring back her money.
我去了她的房子想要把钱给回她
I was kind of ex cited about seeing her again.
想到要见到她我又感到莫名的兴奋
But when I got there...
当我去到那里的时候
...she and her brother had picked up and gone.
她和她的弟弟已经收拾行李离开了
Find a job yet?
还没有找到工作吗?
l ain't studying no job, Odell.
我现在不技工作了欧戴尔
No job? How you gonna live?
不技工作?你要靠什么生活
l got a little money saved up. l'll invest in real estate.
我存了一点钱．我会投资到房地产
-Maybe go into business for myself. -What kind of business?
D也许我会自己做生意D什么生意?
Private investigating.
私人投资
You get in trouble doing that.
做那种生意会遇到麻烦的
Well, like a man told me once:
喂，就像有一次一个男人告诉我
''Step out your door, you're already in trouble.
一定出家门你就已经遇到麻烦
Only thing is, if you're mixed up at the top or not.''
只要这样，如果你被卷进去了你就要占据主导位置
l guess you're right.
我想你是对的
lf you got a friend that you know does bad things, real bad things...
如果你知道你的朋友做了坏事，很坏很坏的事．．．
...and you still keep him as a friend, knowing what he's like...
但是你还是跟他交朋友即使知道他是怎样的人．
...is that wrong?
那样做对不对?
All you got is your friends.
你只是多了一个朋友
What are you doing? You get out of my yard!
你在干什么?滚出我的院子
Get away!
滚出去
That fool knocked down two of my trees. Get away!
那个蠢材砍了我两棵树．滚开
Get on!
快点
You all right?
你还好吧?
I thought about what he said about friends...
我在想你刚才的关于交朋友的一番话…
...and it made sense to me.
我很有感触
Odell goes to church every Sunday, so he would know.
欧戴尔每个星期都上教堂所以他理解的
Later, he challenged me to dominoes. Now, what he do that for?
过了一会，我们一起玩多米诺骨牌．
We got to talking about Texas and fooled around...
我们谈到德克萨斯州还有身边的一些磊事
...and drunk a quart of whiskey.
唱了1／4瓶的威士忌
And I forgot all about Daphne Monet, DeWitt Albright, Carter and them.
我忘记了望芜．摩耐特，戴维新奥尔布赖特，卡特他们所有人
And I sat with my friend...
我跟我的朋友坐在一起
... on my porch...
在我的走廊上
...at my house...
在我家里
...and we laughed a long time.
我们笑了很长一段时间
Subtitles by GELULA & CO., lNC.
格鲁拉电影公司奉献